Okay, thank you, that concludes the SUA meeting, we're now going to move into the regular
meeting in the City Council for today's date and time.
I'm in two as a Proclamation declaring April 18 through 2017, Community Crisis Center
Volunteer Appreciation Week, and hi, hi.
Do you want to make an announcement specifically about that?
Are we just just asking us to vote to approve the Proclamation?
Just asking the Proclamation and its Volunteer Appreciation Month, and we host our volunteer
Appreciation Week during that week that we ask you for the Proclamation, and if we notice
it's a three-day week, so we've changed the week from seven days to three, but we
were able to do that.
Anyway, we just want to say thank you for your support of the Community Crisis Center and our
Volunteer Appreciation Month, so we appreciate you for claiming the period of volunteer.
Do we have much to approve of the Proclamation you do?
And a second, and a second, roll call, please.
Johnson, I'm Weston.
Aye.
Forster, hot, short.
Thank you.
I don't feel as public in touch, I don't feel as public in touch, I don't feel as public in touch, I don't feel as
down for Florence, it was just good addressed the Council on any of the agenda items.
So bear paid nine or four işte an hour and four is a bill.
It's gastric for items five through eleven to be placed on a concept agenda.
I don't have a question.
No question.
Go forward.
I want my chair to ventilate.
I did it a couple of days, but I was reluctant to put it on.
Okay, SEÑắcvert.
We were integrating together.
We did not get any?
There are no other items, and they're paying the most to approve of items 5, 6, and 8 through 11.
Motion to put them there.
Okay.
And I'll second that.
We'll call please.
Joseph.
Aye.
Forster.
And so item 7 is a budget amendment number 1745GF.
For the animal control is seeing the extending of animal shelter donations for maintenance
and repairs at the animal shelter.
I call the leash all the time.
I did talk about that.
I can talk to the rest of the cat.
For a calm.
Would you explain what you explained to me?
I want them to know what was going on over.
What we wanted to do was to be able to do a little renovation for the animal shelter
in order to make it more friendly.
Use a friendly for us to have our spade noodle clinics.
And this is allowing us to use our donations for that renovation.
It just fits them into the category for me.
Yeah.
What it's really going to do is the original design of that had kind of an employee break room and a grooming room.
Really don't use the break room.
that it does tie into the grooming range.
So what we're going to be doing is creating a passage way
into it to create a much larger area.
We're just going to be so much better
when we do the Spain-Newton clinics and things such as that.
So it's basically using some room that originally,
I think they thought they would need something
like a break room that they really don't.
But for the general public and also for animal welfare,
it's going to be a very good improvement for that center.
And our most fun donations restricting
and some wine is that why we need to approve the change.
They were news revenues in that was not budgeted.
And donations that people have specifically paid
for the animal shelter.
OK, so for general use for the animal shelter.
OK.
I would like to point out that we've never used any donations
to supplant monies that the city is already had for the shelter.
So this is why we really appreciate the donations
because this is over and above the money that we had budgeted
for the facility.
And it's really going to end up making it a very much nicer facility.
I think Neil, I think some of that money's yours
and some of that money's mine.
So if I'm listed, I'm sorry, we're all still going
to put candles outside too.
But this money, yes, that is.
But eventually, that's what we're going to do.
We're going to be doing that in June.
OK.
We have a grant that there is a group of people
that are members of the AmeriCorps and they're
going to come in and do the labor.
And we're going to supply the supplies form.
And hopefully, we're going to have 12 outside
Kindle areas for the animals.
We're going to have some on the north side of the old shelter.
And then we're going to have some on the south side of the old
shelter so that we'll be able to have animals outside when it's pretty.
And other clean in their candles and give them a little bit of
run space because they're going to be 4 by 8 by 6 with the tops on them.
So we're going to make some green space formal with that too.
Yeah, to just refresh air.
Yeah, yes.
I agree.
Thank you.
Just keep making it bigger than it.
OK.
Thank you.
So do we have a motion to approve on and set?
Motion to approve there.
And a second?
Second?
Roll up all.
All right.
Forester.
Messed in.
I've chosen.
I have one question in it.
Some regards in this, but it's very simple.
Mende.
I notice on item 8 on the memorandum understanding.
That basically identical to what it was last year.
Nothing's changed.
That's the, that's the, what we've done and what they've done.
It's just actually.
Okay.
Immigrants to the radio.
One last question.
Very simple.
I saw markers here.
I don't know if you know the south top of your head.
And if not, where I'll give you the layers, not anything important.
But do you know how many, I guess it would be more of a city question there.
And how many permits do we give out for, um, probably quite a few.
I was just curious.
I've got.
I don't know, I don't know if I can buy that.
Just, yeah, I'm just curious.
I'll see you up up.
Just curious.
See you have to get that.
I saw Mark's name on there, so I said you didn't advertise Mark.
No, that would never answer.
Now, for this one, this is like one mega gross.
See, I would do that if we could fully count for that.
That's my seven.
Okay.
I'm full of all sorts of associates.
We're all four and all the 14 to conduct a feasibility study
to raise a portion of each tree southwest at the figure grounds.
Well, you shouldn't, Sean, and do you do
to make an introductory comments about our meetings?
Well, a little bit out of name.
One thing I do want to mention the mark is that we just approved the gross sales
and the consent agenda.
So, you're welcome to study, but I'm just going to be sure you know,
you got to do this, got to do this, got to do this, got to do this, got to do this.
I would appreciate that.
I would appreciate being able to introduce to you
and to do this slide I'm very, very briefly if I can.
About two weeks ago, the mayor and I were in a meeting with the director about
the regional engineer had of Tulsa for this area.
Senator Burtström also represented the warring.
They're also represented as available from the Intertrial Council.
And there were a number of discussions about some projects in my
and a road project.
So, one of Steve O'Neill's Boulevard at Tark Creek being able to elevate that above the
base flood elevation.
That's going to be a major project, but you've got to start somewhere and you've got to start working
on that.
There's been a lot of reporting, a very good reporting of the news record about the intersection
at Steve O'Neill's and the Turnpike and 69A, improving that intersection.
I think our last meeting, Tyler, provided an update that we provided to O'Dott,
about being able to do some immediate work on those intersections to provide some
protective turns, but also the intersection frankly needs to be rebuilt.
And we're working with them right now.
We hope within about two or three years that project can go forward.
But I think everybody's aware that, and we talked to O'Dott about the fact that they are going to be
doing the re-decking of the state highway 125 bridge over the NIO show river starting in 2018.
And when that happens, that bridge is going to be closed down.
So, we're already talking about routing traffic over the other bridge on 69A,
being able to get to the south side of town.
Well, one thing that we've been talking to them talking to O'Dott about is the fact that if that bridge is closed,
this will be an opportune time to raise and elevate the approaches to the bridge.
And just little over two years that I've been here, we've had to close state highway 125,
three times because of high water.
That's becoming a chronic item.
If that approach was above the base flood elevation or at least even elevated,
we wouldn't have situations where we're closing off.
south part of town, especially when you're talking about emergency access. The response we have
from ODOT on that was they saw that was a good idea but with the state and their procurement
process they said they'd have to do a feasibility study and then a number of other permitting
and it just takes time in this project with a bridge deck he's going to be next year.
So I offer to them and I ask them that since we do have an engineering firm on board, if we
proceeded into the feasibility study that was something that if they could look at the way we
would do the feasibility study and approve it and then accept the feasibility study. In other words,
when it is stamped by the engineer that they take that as a feasibility study, if that could
move the project along, if they indicated that they would be able to do that. So this is why
we have decided before you tonight. This is probably one of our best chances with little
interruption of traffic flows since we're already going to be interrupting traffic flow
because of the bridge to try to elevate that part of the highway. Probably of course this is what
the feasibility study will do that we anticipate is really going to be more of an earthen dam with some
conduit underneath of water could pass between it and make sure that when we have our high water
events in that area that we're not having to close off the road and people can get to their homes or
emergency access can get to the south part of town. So that's what this agenda item is it would be
pay for our app on web funds and it seems that ideally I love it if the state would just proceed on it
but that's just not the fact that their procurement takes much longer than our procurement does
and we believe it's a good way to try to move that project along for the benefit of the entire community.
Hello? I'd just add a little bit to that. What we're talking about tonight is just the
engineering part there's still some environmental wars. It was like the permitting that they have
meeting that would have to be done and the state would have to do those things. So this hopefully
if we approve this was being the process up but there's still other work that would be done that the city will
not be responsible for that what I would call preliminary work. And once it's done it would be a
state project not a state project. Yep. You may have commented that as far as they will accept
the study. I now speak out for a situation with the steps for bridge in commerce there's some issues
over there with some communication to engineering firm in the state and now it's all doing this. I know.
I don't want to pay for $3,000 for something that I'm not going to get concrete that they're going to accept
something like that. I agree with you whole whole night. That's very touch. We're asking you to
proceed with this but before we actually get this starting I want to be sure we're sitting down with
their dog that they approve of the methodology they approve of the people that are going to be doing this
they know exactly what we're going to do
how the study's going to be done
and then they will accept that in other words,
when there's a stamp by the engineer when Sean stamps that
that they will take that and they will accept it
because I'm exactly like you, this is all right.
So I don't know how many put out until we know for sure
that they will, that's exactly the way I do it,
because I don't want to go through this,
I don't want to spend almost $50,000
and have owed our civil, it's not good enough.
I know there's some issues over there
and I don't want to get caught into that.
I agree.
I don't know the, we can say there won't be any money
span.
I mean, Austin's going to have to do the little bit
of preliminary stuff just to say, here's what we're thinking
of state, this is past master or vice versa, exactly.
Is that a fair statement?
That's great.
Okay.
But certainly not.
But not 40,000.
Not 40,000.
I mean, I hope I've been interested in this one.
I'm a little bit of a saying.
I think you're right to be nervous about that.
I'm too.
Right.
In fact, when we concluded with our meeting,
did it in the state meet with the county and I mean,
I don't know what the outcome otherwise, but they met right after we
did.
And the topic was steps forward.
That's exactly it.
And I think it's a chance to.
Yeah.
How long did they work for continuing to work on that?
Practically.
Thanks, man.
How long's the bridge going to be down for a day?
I think it could be down almost as long as a year.
This is a major project, but they're anticipating once
the stunt.
This bridge will have a lifespan of probably a far out of our
steps.
Yeah.
They said 20 to 30 years.
They're almost doing.
Well, you might be.
Yeah.
I won't be saying anything.
I won't be doing it.
I might be doing it, but I might not be driving.
I'm going to be a sort of questions.
Where we're going to get ready and birth for the Schwartz very fast?
We can certainly ask.
I think this is, frankly, this is one of these meetings where times of the essence
and you could see the look on their face about the fact that what they would have to go through
with procurement.
And many times for projects like this, if the city helps with some things, you can move it up
to the ladder and get it done quicker.
And that's why we offered to do this.
So, it'd be nice if we can get it reimbursed, but even if we don't, I think it's going to be
money will spend.
If we can get this done at the same time, the bridge is being done.
Yeah.
Then do you have anything to add?
I don't know that you had any further conversations since we met.
No, no.
Okay, thank you.
I would like to add one thing, though.
You know, when we're talking about wanting to be sure they accepted it and everything like that, that's
it's usually important.
But I do think mayor and I hope you agree with me that it did seem like Oda was very open
to this and very open to working with us.
So, I don't want anybody to come away with this thinking that they were putting up barriers
in fact with anything, I think they appreciated the fact.
Yeah, I would like to be kind of excited that we were willing to take the lead at least initial.
because they just, the bill ofocracy just dictates that there's no way they can get what they
need and done and still stick to the 2018 schedule.
Because that's one of the things that, well, do you want us to push the bridge back to you
when we don't want you to be decking back a year or so?
So this was an alternative that allowed them to keep to that schedule and thus explore whether,
you know, as I said, the feasibility of it.
So I'm sure you keep us up there.
I just would ask that, you know, any time we hear more on this or, you should have the communication
aspect of that.
I'd like to know where we're at on it.
A great.
I'm sure while we're on the side of the dumpster, no third chiefs are here.
I don't know what it looks, Robert.
I, I, I usually have contingency plans for emergency, well, that, uh, decking, we decking is being
down in the bridge.
Yes, we will go around just like we do down with waters up for flooded.
We won't have anything really stationed out there.
And I'll probably, we don't really have anything out there that we would really need to station
for.
I think what we're talking about is a few more minutes.
And, um, now if we have an issue with 69 hours, something, yes, we definitely station out
there.
But in a normal conditions, Robert, we have the additional funds that they can't leave on.
Okay, Dr. Holmes.
Yeah.
What?
Okay.
That's an option.
What do I have there?
Okay.
So Alicia and Sean, I know we've kind of talked this through for our own benefit.
We have, so tell us the technical side of it.
But in the money side.
Okay.
The one thing that I want to be sure enough, when Sean and I first started talking about this, we
made it very clear before I ever started with this scope of work that this was something
that the state was going to have to accept.
And then we're going to have to do it to ODOT standards.
And so going into it, initially, even that before we ever came here, that you needed
it to be ODOT acceptable.
So most of you know that your flood maps are currently being revised.
I've been talking to Chris Randolph, who's been talking to FEMA, and I actually have the proposed
effective model for your new maps.
Our goal would be to use that model to study the impacts of raising 125.
There's no reason to use the current effective model, and these maps are new next year.
So it's kind of a waste of everybody's time and money.
So the goal is to use the proposed effective model.
Raise 125 and see what we need to do to keep the flood plane where it is now.
We're actually working on establishing the floodway along the O show through my Emma.
So that means we can't.
We have a zero rise, a no rise condition that we have to meet for this.
So basically we have to open it up somewhere else, to let that water through.
So with pipes or something else.
That's something we're going to have to look into.
Any of the FEMA revision work that needs to be done.
We'll have to discuss that later.
We were kind of under a different understanding when we started.
The thing that would just take this, I'm going to incorporate it into the new maps.
We may actually have to go through the revision steps to get your maps revised after this is done.
So, it's a kind of where we're at.
We're working with FEMA though.
We do have their data.
So, we've got some work with.
We can hit the ground running.
So, they're data being how long it looks.
Yeah, basically they're mud model.
That their engineering is built.
I have a copy of it.
And Chris Randolph reported me today that we may not even see some of these maps officially until the first of 2018.
Correct.
It's been pushed back quite a bit.
I think they're redoing their engineering.
But what Sean is doing is being extra careful to make sure that we're going with the new maps because we'd hate to do that.
And then find out they raised the maps and we still have an issue.
So, how optimistic do you feel?
I'm afraid to answer right now because I really don't know honestly.
That waterway over the road, that cross-sectional area, we've got to make up that different somewhere else.
So, that's how you're going to create that no-rise commission.
And we'll get into that and see what we've got to do to make this work.
So, we do have a profile that Tyler was able to find a conceptual on that profile.
4125 that I did a while back.
So, we're probably going to start with that and see if what that would get us in there.
That water floods all the way down to the little bridge.
We're done with the softball.
Are you thinking of retaining that bridge?
Are we looking at another bridge?
Build?
I don't know.
It depends on what the new model.
I've seen what the new elevation is going to be.
But I haven't seen the extent of the new floodplain.
So, I'm not sure how much further down on 25 that's going to run now.
And Dean, we talk about, so you mentioned earlier, it's flooded three times in two years.
And certainly at the end of the road is what I can call it there.
Exactly.
But as far as flooding further out, whatever direction that is, I mean that hasn't happened.
I think a year ago December it came very close.
That was the last time we had to close Steve Owens for a short period of time with water over it.
I don't recall that the water actually crossed at that location, but I think it came very close.
So, you know, that eventually, I'm not going to have to look at that as well.
But that could even be a separate project for them.
But this...
So there's the idea of who knows the practical and if we can cut by 80 percent, the amount of times that was closed, that's a major improvement.
Exactly.
We can't get to 100 percent, we'll get to 80 percent.
Right.
And that's something else that needs to be discussed later.
Maybe we don't get to that hundred-year event.
Maybe we can get to something just a little bit.
All right.
You remember, every time we've closed off one twenty-five, it's not even been,
and since I've been here, it's not even near one hundred-year event.
I don't know if it's sad to say I don't know that it was a hundred-year event.
I'm a man.
From what I understand it wasn't.
I'm scared of your thinking about it.
Yeah.
Okay, any other issue or show anything else to add?
So you asked him for approval tonight for the four, four, three thousand?
Yes, but again, we will have all of those assurances before we really get the project underway
and make sure that this is something that O.D. meets about standards and that O.D. will accept.
Okay.
And Sean, you're comfortable that you're not going to have to spend that full amount to get the answers we need.
No, not the initial meeting.
I'll have my engineers that are going to work on this.
We'll set up a meeting with Dean and O.D., we'll get together.
We'll keep this thing around first before we ever...
Okay.
And I think with your attitude, I'm not uncomfortable with that.
I think they're going to be very good to work with on this.
Okay.
Any other questions for any of them?
Everybody comfortable with what we've talked about?
Come forward.
I have to make a motion to approve.
May.
Second.
I'll second.
We'll call.
Sean Pint.
Aye.
Question.
Thank you.
I have 13.
I'm out of here.
We'll be O.D.E.Q.
For a new nation of voters sitting in the parking areas along the sea south west.
And approve the same individual sun and Alicia.
Sometimes I go, you all did an approval for D.E.Q. to test redric park.
And they've now done that.
And they have found two hotspots.
And this is.
Redric centennial park.
And they found two hotspots.
Ironically, it appears that it's the driveways of a couple of those houses that we took out.
Whenever we were doing the walking park.
And so they found those.
They're wanting to go in at no cost to the city and remediate those.
That's what this MOU is for 103.
They also found a couple of hotspots on 418 C Southwest.
It's a gravel area there.
And they're wanting to basically do the same thing.
Let's go in and do the remediation there.
Similar to how they've done in the alleys.
A little history on it.
It was federal federal has stepped back from the remediation and turned it over.
to ODQ, so they are taking it over and this is, as far as I know, the first thing that they've done in the city of Miami on their part of the remediation.
Again, there will be no cost to the city. We ran it past our contract lawyer, she had a couple of questions about, would there be any residual contamination like when...
Yeah, I've show came up, but when Tarkree came up, and we spoke to Brian and Brian said that they had tested all of Centennial Park, and there was absolutely nothing there that was above their levels other than these two spots.
And we all know that Tarkree has flooded there over and over again, so he's comfortable saying that he doesn't think there will be any more.
And he feels the same way about the right team. He doesn't think that once this is remediated, there will be the danger of it recontaminating, so that this is just for them to be able to get permission from us to go and do that.
Can anybody, I know they've done those in the past, and a lot of people's had their guidelines and so forth, or they've done the other way.
Well, they still come out and test somebody's property if they requested it.
They didn't say anything to me about that. I am sure if someone wanted to have their driveway tested. I would be more than happy to give them Brian's number, and they could speak directly to him if they still have that program going because that would be all through ODEQ.
Can we check out that thing, see if we can find it?
Once they have their driveway tested, I know there's a lot down, but there's still maybe some people out there that they want to do.
And there could be, I know that they tested mine, so I'm sure that I can get a hold of Brian and give you an update on whether or not they're still doing it.
Because that would be the whole crux of it, whether or not they're doing that part of it, or if it was something that was completely discontinued whenever federal government would do it.
Is there a time frame when they want to remediate these areas?
They're wanting to do it before October.
And we all know that before they start on the, is it no DQ that's going to start on the ODEQ?
No DQ, but different divisions.
Different divisions.
That with the ODEQ, we're working with two different divisions on the ODEQ on that project.
Yeah, we're working with the gentleman by the name of Brian.
But they said October somewhere.
Well, they wanted to have it done by October.
So I would figure they're probably going to do it this summer when it's warm and the weather's good.
Okay.
I have no doubts.
Okay, do we have a motion to approve item 13?
Make a motion.
Second, I'll second.
I'll call please.
Forster.
Western.
Hi.
Johnson.
Short.
Five.
I have a 14, that I'll treat maintenance program.
We'll go ahead and get some things that we're going to look for.
I'll go ahead and go ahead and go ahead and go ahead.
Well, Alicia's doing that.
I asked her and Mike to give you an update because we're getting very close to bringing some items to you.
And we wanted to be sure that we have ample time to discuss.
Sample time to, if there are any modifications or changes or things that you want us to take a look at.
Especially based on the work that Sean did for us earlier this year.
Actually, late last year, I should say, you know, making sure that you understand what we're trying to do to accomplish what
his strategy was based on history to analysis.
So the point here we're making is we really wanted to kind of give you an idea of what we're thinking.
Answer any questions tonight.
But also just give you an idea to think about it.
Have the public take a look at it too.
Give us some background.
So we'll do bring it to you.
We'll have a discussion.
Any modifications we need to make.
To make sure we're on the right track.
What do you, when you say the public, what are you looking for?
What are thoughts on?
I'll do it.
You know, I think so.
Yes, I think that it's always helpful to, if somebody kind of gives us some viewpoint about,
Hey, what about this street or that street?
That you hear that.
Absolutely.
We have an opportunity to take a look at that as before we go into that.
That was one thing I've heard significantly as how do you make these decisions?
Yeah.
And, you know, we're going to tell you how we make these decisions and do it very transparently.
But also to have an opportunity to somebody say, hey, can you look at this area?
And give an answer to that as well.
I think I think that's great.
As long as we're including the public and I want to think that they got to understand the depth of what we went into to pick these.
And it was just not random.
And, and the other thing too is we're trying to move ahead that we can actually get some things started next month, literally in April.
Or excuse me, in May.
So, Alicia, you've got to take that for you.
Okay.
So, the method to the madness.
One of the things that we remember is when you get to a certain point on a street of deterioration, that's there.
It's going to be there.
It's going to be there now and it's going to be there next summer.
We're trying very hard to save our streets that are saveable with micro-surfacing and crack ceiling, so that we're doing the best we can with the money that we've got.
And get the, I hate to say at the biggest bang for our buck.
So, what you see on here, what you see is, Sean has very, very kindly.
What you think is map a little bit and you'll see these bright red streets.
This is the ones that we're proposing for our micro-surfacing for 2017.
Can you scroll it just a little bit, Tyler?
Maybe more than a little bit, I didn't realize it was that big so we have the streets out in the southwest part of town
we have
There you go, and we have streets in the northwest if if you will click on the
two and the the two
Okay, so you see I want to concentrate on this so you can kind of get an idea you can see these two's
Those are the ones that Sean determined would would be okay with just the crack ceiling
We as a city have a crack ceiling machine and we're going to try to crack cellies and if you'll
You'll see where we get these trees and these two's done. This neighborhood will be pretty much
Done and complete and we can step away from that for a while and be able to concentrate on our fours and our files
So if you'll take us back up north
The trees the blue the choose the blue and those the crack sales
So if you will see when when you get to look into this and and you see
You can come over here and you can see this too now
Some of these streets and you see that are three's that we don't have in red
Those are concrete streets and concrete streets will really don't take the micro surfacing that well
But some of the concrete streets are the twos and we can crack cell those and we can also replace the individual panels
Like you were talking about at one point in time, but our
Method is we're trying to save as many of the twos and the threes as we possibly can so that next year we can concentrate
Picture number fours
See all that that lights up that's what we're trying to concentrate on next year
So if we can take care of the twos in the threes this year
That will give us the ability to concentrate on the fours and the fives next year and
Can we get over in in the area?
So what you're trying to say is by
Doing the twos and threes now they won't turn into
Yes, exactly and that's the that's when I was telling you that
Wasn't once it's gone it's gone and we can't save it but we can save those twos and threes and not
End up happened to fix more that are fours and fives because we were over here
Trying to fix them four and fives this year
We can save those twos and threes
So you're telling me all fours and fives are receivable by crack saving a micro-surf see no
Or are
Okay, so we don't deal with that. It's only the twos and threes
The fours and fives would probably be milling over the way
Exactly, so that's kind of the method to our madness you all have a toddler can you scroll back down?
into the south part of town.
Yes, sir.
I'm just curious of how much of parts of the,
in your, there are fours and fives there.
Would you like me to put them on the floor?
Just fours and fives on the south part, okay.
There's a fours and fives.
So there is a few there out there.
There's given me the end of the thing
that maybe out there is probably some
of the best 20 Centanus,
because I didn't, yes, I didn't believe it.
And actually, I was gonna say,
if you look at,
that's what the people don't understand
that's on this side of town,
that yes, we are constrained,
because the roads all are in better shape,
but we're trying to keep them there.
It's not that we're trying to take away from them.
We're not all, not all, and we did,
when we were doing this, we looked at the neighborhoods
that honestly were better streets
so that we could save them,
fully well known that when we got up into the older part
of town in the west side of town,
we're looking at a lot of, a million overlay,
and things like that.
And our goal is to put this out to bid,
next year say, January, when people are hungry or,
and we might get better kids on this mill,
and overlay, because that's gonna be a big chunk.
And we're also gonna concentrate on our west central,
which is a utility and a street project together,
where you are working on possibly getting some grant funding
for our truck route, so we'll be able to do that.
And those are things that we are trying to concentrate
on for next year.
And also mainstream around the coalmen,
and also the drainage issues,
so I know Sean's trying to find a solution for.
All right, so we've got that study back
and we're working on getting that taken care of.
We do want feedback, which is exactly why I gave you
that list of the proposed streets, look at it,
see what you think about it, if there's some that,
you know, we are very flexible
and we want to be flexible.
One thing, just to see the big room for Rex plot,
which is at the airport, well, we found out tonight.
These guys are proved, and they're gonna start
doing construction on the airport.
Well, there's gonna be a lot of heavy traffic down there.
So doing Rex plot right now is not a good idea.
We're gonna wait until that's done.
And then we're gonna see what the road's like
and kind of reevaluate it then,
because there will be a lot of heavy traffic on that
while they're doing that construction.
But that's just an idea to give you,
we are flexible about this,
and it's kind of a living, breathing, working document.
You said that you had a truck route.
Is that one of the roads that we would talk about,
I think, in the past, that was looked to be all the way down?
Yes, we're currently working with Grand Gate Way right now.
There is a federal program basically is called High and White,
and it's for arterial roads that are connected
to a federal highway, of course, that's 69,
and carries commercial traffic.
So it's a high emphasis right now with ODOT in a project with ODOT.
So we are in the process at this point of...
working with Grand Gateway to get the truck route into that program, which would allow federal funds to be used basically reconstructed.
In 2018 project.
I'm just trying to put it in.
Probably 2018 to 2020.
We probably had the splash pad up and running before that project.
And we've had a street counter going for the week to kind of give them an idea of just how much traffic really does.
We did it for two days here two weeks ago.
And we had over 9,000 cars in two days and that was a Tuesday and Wednesday.
So we're trying to demonstrate exactly how important that road is to help us with the funding through the grant program.
Securities will those funds just cover the street or will it cover the infrastructure underneath?
It's the infrastructure.
It's basically a reconstruction of that road.
This is this would be a major major project, but we would really need federal funding for.
Not just a resurfacing.
In fact, if anything in some areas it would probably also be a widening of the street as well.
Because right now it's a narrow street when we've all been on it when we pass a semi or something we know how tight it is.
It's really designed for more 21st century commerce and making sure that we're moving commercial traffic through there properly.
And that's what the truck routes for and that's what these funds are for.
I believe Oklahoma in the next year or two will probably have about $200 million for projects like this.
And we're hoping to get a share of it to rebuild our truck route.
If for some reason we chose to start putting our electric underground, would that be something that would be covered as well?
Maybe it really I don't know that.
I think it would probably be dependent on the requirements of the grant and our ability to be able to do that.
We could certainly look into it, but I don't have an answer that it would or would not at this point.
But I think if we are looking at widening probably relocation of some of our utilities.
I mean, all too often we have some of our water and sewer winds under the roads and they really shouldn't be.
So if there's some relocations along that line, I could even see some of the structures along there that might be purchased and removed to be able to have that as a wider road.
But it's something that really needs to be done and it's and these projects are slow, but I'm hoping that there's going to be more and more money out there for infrastructure.
And we can certainly use it.
You know the questions about the plan, the road plan, the priorities.
I didn't 15 is due business, any new business.
I had a question that says we don't have staff reports on their well, Microsoft did we have a water line break on West Michael Bay.
We were doing a tap for we put in the new water line on D Street and we have to tap.
in the new main into the old main that the main that feeds down central so we do a tap right there to make that line hot
Okay, so that's all we had to close down this section. Okay
Okay, any other new business
Any
Okay, then any city manager
Okay, should I help anybody watching we'll vote within the next 45 minutes?
Yeah, yeah, keep in the way over
I'm 18 is executive session for soon to 25 or less section to a little 7 B3 we're discussing the purchase of a period of real property for economic development purposes
We are mostly going to executive session for the reasons listed on agenda item 18 motion to a primary
Second
Thank you
Go call please
Johnson
Forester
Weston
Five
Okay, we are out of the
Second
Six 42 p.m.
There's no action
To be taken either 19 is a permit to have us to adjourn
Motion to adjourn
Second
We'll call please
Forester
Weston
Johnson
Five
Thank you